# Miranda Montez

New York, NY 10028 | 218-390-3779 | monte141@uw.edu

#### **S**UMMARY

Versatile professional in pursuit of MLIS degree with four years of experience working in a library. Background includes performing all tasks associated with circulation, reference, instruction, and interlibrary loan. Accustomed to managing data and working with databases. Extremely organized, efficient, and detail-oriented.

#### **E**XPERIENCE

LONG ISLAND UNIVERSITY BROOKLYN, NEW YORK, NY

September 2018-present

# **Library Graduate Assistant**

- Assist at the Ask-a-Librarian Reference Desk, answering questions via in-person, phone, email, and chat.
- Lead Library Instructional Classes.
- Create and Maintain LibGuide pages for website.

WHITNEY MUSEUM OF AMERICAN ART, NEW YORK, NY

January 2018-May 2018

## **Library Intern**

- Perform circulation tasks, such as mail, checking books in and out, and customer service.
- Create and organize MARC Records for files and books.
- Utilize Voyageur Circulation and Cataloging Databases.

DR. CORRIE HORSHINSKI, D.C., CHIROPRACTOR, NEW YORK, NY

November 2016 – July 2018

#### Receptionist

St. Louis County Public Health and Human Services, Duluth, MN

May 2015 - June 2016

#### Information Specialist I

- Entered customer information into databases (Compass Pilot, OnBase, RightFax, Maxis, and Curam).
- Received and processed all incoming phone calls, mail, and faxes.

KATHRYN A. MARTIN LIBRARY, Duluth, MN

August 2011 - May 2015

## Interlibrary Loan Specialist – Lead, Circulation Staff

- Utilized databases, including Alma, ILLiad, Ariel, and Aleph, to perform circulation tasks.
- Managed the opening and closing of the building and supervised several student workers as they checked in/out materials, interacted with patrons, and organized books.

# **EDUCATION**

University of Washington

September 2017 - May 2020 (expected)

# **Master of Library and Information Science**

Study Abroad Short Term: iSchool in the Netherlands, Amsterdam, Netherlands

University of Minnesota – Duluth

May 2015

### **Bachelor of Arts in Political Science and International Studies**

GPA: 3.86/4.0

Study Abroad Academic Year: University of Worcester, Worcester, England

## LANGUAGE AND COMPUTER SKILLS

Word Spanish (limited working proficiency) Microsoft Windows Excel English (native) Apple OSX/macOS

PowerPoint Typing speed of 68 WPM Scan, fax and copy machine experience